Guide to the Stanford University, School of Humanities and Sciences, Humanities Special Programs, Records SC0096
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
Stanford University, School of Humanities and Sciences, Humanities Special Programs, records
1946-1969
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
Stanford University. School of Humanities and Sciences
SC0096
6 Linear Feet
Correspondence, minutes, budgets, sample exams, chronologies, and other records largely pertaining to the graduate Honor's Program and Religious Studies. There are also materials pertaining to the Pacific Coast Committee for the Humanities, 1951-67.
Immediate Source of Acquisition note
Administrative transfers, 1971, 2016.
Information about Access
This collection is open for research.
Biographical/Historical Sketch
The Special Programs in Humanities included an undergraduate and graduate Honor's Program in Humanities, Hispanic American Studies, Pacific-Asiatic and Russian Studies, and Religious Studies.
Description of the Collection
Correspondence, minutes, budgets, sample exams, chronologies, and other records largely pertaining to the graduate Honor's Program and Religious Studies. There are also materials pertaining to the Pacific Coast Committee for the Humanities, 1951-67. Accession ARCH-2017-085 consists of records regarding the Interdisciplinary Studies in Humanities (ISH) program.
Humanities -- Study and teaching.; Stanford University. School of Humanities and Sciences; Stanford University. School of Humanities and Sciences; Stanford University. School of Humanities and Sciences; Pacific Coast Committee for the Humanities.
- Records
  - Admissions, 1968 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Admissions (complaints, etc.) (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Admissions minorities, 1968-69 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Admissions, other universities, 1967 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Graduate Program in Humanities [GPH] – administration, correspondence, 1963-67 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Honors Program agenda, 1967-68 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Aims of GPH (1 of 2) (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Aims of GPH (2 of 2) (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Archives to Sept. 1953 (1951-53) (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - ASSU, 1968 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Book orders and letters about books for humanities courses, 1955-63 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Budgets, 1956-67 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Estimated budget, 1960-63 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - GPH – Committee, 1954-62 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - GPH – Committee, winter 1965 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - GPH – Committee, 1965-57 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - GPH – Committee meetings, 1967 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - GPH – Committee correspondence, 1963-64 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - GPH – Correspondence, 1965 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Correspondence, Clarence Faust (Fund for the Advancement of Education), 1953-65 (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - GPH – Correspondence, interdepartmental, 1959-63 (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Correspondence, interdepartmental, 1964-68 (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - Dean of Graduate Division, 1958-68 (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - GPH – Dean of Humanities and Sciences, 1962 (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - GPH – Expansion and fellowship needs, 1953-63 (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - Evaluation of program, 1954-59 (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - GPH – final comprehensive examinations, samples of, 1963-66 (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - Humanities and Sciences Faculty, Admissions Committee, 1967 (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - Finances and Religious Studies Funding, 1963-69 (Box 1, Folder 29)
  - GPH – Foundations: correspondence, reports, 1962-65 (Box 1, Folder 30)
  - Fund for the Advancement of Education – financial reports, 1963-65 (Box 1, Folder 31)
  - Fund for the Advancement of Education Graduate Program Humanities 70-4401-25 Budget, 1954 – Aug. 1960 (Box 1, Folder 32)
  - Fund for the Advancement of Education Graduate Program Humanities 70-4401-25 Budget, Oct. 1960 (Box 1, Folder 33)
  - Government and higher education, 1962-64 (Box 1, Folder 34)
  - Grad testing, 1967 (Box 1, Folder 35)
  - Guide for Term or Research Paper (S.U. publication), 1937 (Box 1, Folder 36)
  - Humanities council, 1960 (Box 1, Folder 37)
  - Humanities Institute, 1965 (Box 1, Folder 38)
  - Humanities and Sciences proposal, Prof. Kocher, 1963-64 (Box 1, Folder 39)
  - Committee on University Libraries, 1968 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Library new building, 1969 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - GPH Library – books ordered, 1966 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - GPH – Library budget, 1965 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - GPH – Library correspondence, 1963-66 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - GPH – Library purchases, 1960-64 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - National Defense Education Act, 1959-65 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - National Endowment for Humanities, 1965-66 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - National Humanities Foundation, 1965 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - GPH – Mailing List (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - GPH – Master copies of various forms, notices, etc., 1961-63 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Meetings with students, 1959 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Other graduate humanities programs, 1961-64 (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Placement material (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - GPH – Provost's office, 1965 (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - GPH – Statistics, 1953-68 (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - Teachers, active, 1953-60 (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - GPH – Teaching positions, 1958-64 (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - GPH – Teaching positions, 1967-68 (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - Chronological Record of Development of Graduate Honors Program in Humanities, 1951-53 (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - Honors Program in Humanities committee, minutes, 1946-47 (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - Honors Program in Humanities committee, minutes, 1948-49 (Box 2, Folder 22)
  - Honors Program in Humanities committee, minutes, 1950-51 (Box 2, Folder 23)
  - Honors Program in Humanities committee, minutes, 1952-56 (Box 2, Folder 24)
  - Honors Program in Humanities committee, minutes, 1956-57 (Box 2, Folder 25)
  - Honors Program in Humanities committee, minutes, 1958-60 (Box 2, Folder 26)
  - American Council of Learned Societies, Pacific Coast Committee for Humanities [PCCH], 1951-52 (Box 2, Folder 27)
  - American Council of Learned Societies, Pacific Coast Committee for Humanities [PCCH], 1952-66 (Box 2, Folder 28)
  - PCCH Conference on "Reason and Values" 1952 (includes text of talks given) (Box 2, Folder 29)
  - PCCH Spring Conference, 1954 (Box 2, Folder 30)
  - PCCH Conference (Has the Pacific Coast an Identifiable Culture?), 1958 (Box 2, Folder 31)
  - PCCH TV Conference, 1952 (1 of 2) (Box 2, Folder 32)
  - PCCH TV Conference, 1952 (2 of 2) (Box 2, Folder 33)
  - PCCH TV Conference II, 1953 (Box 2, Folder 34)
  - Pacific Spectator – publication permission correspondence, 1964-67 (Box 2, Folder 35)
  - Religion, 1956-67 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Religion, 1953-55 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Religion, 1946-52 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Religion, Edwin M. Good correspondence, 1957-62 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Religion Appeal – general (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Religion – 1960 Canvas, 1960-61 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Religion Committee, 1952-68 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Religion Committee, Agenda (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Miller, Alexander, correspondence re fundraising, 1953 (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Religion – Credit Evaluation, 1958 (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - Religion – current [assorted reports, memoranda, correspondence], 1959-64 (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - Religion – Curriculum, 1961-62 (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - Religion – Danforth Foundation, 1960-62 (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - Religion – Expansion, 1962-66 (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - Religion – Financial Sources, 1953 (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - Religion – General Studies, 1955-68 (Box 3, Folder 16)
  - Religious Studies – Graduate Program, 1967-70 (Box 3, Folder 17)
  - Religious Studies, Graduate Program I – Inquiries A-E, 1966-68 (Box 3, Folder 18)
  - Religious Studies, Graduate Program I – Inquiries F-K, 1966-68 (Box 3, Folder 19)
  - Religious Studies, Graduate Program I – Inquiries L-R, 1966-68 (Box 3, Folder 20)
  - Religious Studies, Graduate Program I – Inquiries S-Z, 1966-68 (Box 3, Folder 21)
  - Oriental Religions (search material) (Box 3, Folder 22)
  - Religion – Staff correspondence: John W. Dodds, 1955-64 (Box 3, Folder 23)
  - Religion – Staff correspondence: Alexander Miller, 1952 (Box 3, Folder 24)
  - Religion – Staff correspondence: Alexander Miller, 1953 (Box 3, Folder 25)
  - Religion – Staff correspondence: Alexander Miller, 1954 (Box 3, Folder 26)
  - Religion – Staff correspondence: Alexander Miller, 1955 (Box 3, Folder 27)
  - Religion – Staff Search material, 1960-61 (Box 3, Folder 28)
  - Religion, Teaching inquiries, 1960-65 (Box 3, Folder 29)
  - Religion, Teaching inquiries, 1951-57 (Box 3, Folder 30)
  - Religion, Teaching inquiries, 1949-50 (Box 3, Folder 31)
  - Religious Studies – Teaching applications, 1968 (1 of 3) (Box 3, Folder 32)
  - Religious Studies – Teaching applications, 1968 (2 of 3) (Box 3, Folder 33)
  - Religious Studies – Teaching applications, 1968 (3 of 3) (Box 3, Folder 34)
  - Religious Studies – Teaching applications, 1967 (Box 3, Folder 35)
  - Religious Studies – Teaching application, Paul Tillich, 1958-61 (Box 3, Folder 36)
  - Trusts, Cleared, 1951-57 (Box 3, Folder 37)
  - Trusts, to be cleared, 1953-54 (Box 3, Folder 38)
- Additional Records, Accession ARCH_2017_085
  Scope and Contents
  Records regarding Interdisciplinary Studies in Humanities (ISH) program.
  - Humanities Brochures, 1955-1958 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Humanities Newsletters, 1953-1982 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - GPH/ Western Culture, 1979 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - GPH - Grad students Teaching Experience, 1990 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - ISH - majors, undated (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Concentration Guidelines, undated (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Humanities Honors Essay Guidelines, undated (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - GPH Reform, 1970-1978 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - ISH clippings, 2009 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Published Essays, 1988 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Copyrights, 1991-2010 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Guidelines for G.P.H Rep., 2003 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - GPH Requirements (also grad auth), 2009 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - GPH Handbook, undated (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Joint Degree Question, undated (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Symposium General, undated (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - GPH Alum Responses, 1999 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Reflections Collg, 2007-2008 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - GPH Collag, 2009-2010 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Colloq: Mimesis history, undated (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Hum100, 2009 (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - ISH Closure, 2009-2010 (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - DLCL Proposal, 2007-2009 (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - IHUM, etc and HSP, 1997-2000 (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - ISH Handouts Honors Program, undated (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - PICH - program in intellectual cultural history, 2009 (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - Berkeley in the 60's, undated; 1 videotape(s) (VHS) (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - Humanities Honor Essay Lists, 2003-2008 (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - Lerner - Honors Essay, 2010 (Box 1, Folder 29)